STEVEN E. MOORE

4 Independence Court, Marlton, NJ 08053 steven_moore@hotmail.com

notmail.com 856-341-6812 (C)

SUMMARY

Over 20+ years of experience in Operations Management and Customer Service. Recognized as a proven leader. Received numerous nominations and awards due to my "outgoing personality and sincerity", "working diligently to grow customer satisfaction", "outstanding role model", "building great relationships with his team", "upbeat attitude" and for being "a real champion for the customers".

- Planning / Forecasting
- Problem Solving

856-985-8559 (H)

- Training / Development
- Sales & Profit Enhancement
- P&L Management / Analysis
- Team Building / Staff Retention
- Leadership
- Operations
- Loss Prevention

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STAPLES, Marlton, NJ

Copy and Print Center Manager

2007 to 2013

Instrumental in roll out of a new Copy and Print Center (CPC) concept for Staples. Managed CPC in a fast paced retail environment. Earned role as trusted advisor for over 75 managed accounts with annual spending of up to \$25,000. Established myself as the "go to person" for the Staples CPC's in district. Regularly fielded calls from other centers for guidance on procedures and to troubleshoot problems. Relied upon for training copy and print associates for all Staples stores in the district, training new Copy and Print Center Sales Managers, and professional outside sales representatives new to the copy and print industry.

- Ranked as #1 Copy and Print Center Sales Manager for two consecutive years with sales 358% above company average. Utilized SalesForce.com to effectively manage accounts and build relationships that resulted in double digit year over year growth of these accounts.
- ➤ Grew sales by 5 % over a five year period, exceeded profit budget by 7.5%; and, customer satisfaction scores were consistently above company average and company goal by 10 %.
- Analyzed P&L and identified numerous opportunities in sales categories and cost reduction to increase profitability. Identified corporate accounting error which resulted in \$28,000 increase to profit of the CPC.
- Excelled in numerous internal company measures such as: loss prevention audit was 100% for three consecutive years, training compliance was 100% for two consecutive years; and, rewards penetration consistently at 120% of the district average.
- Responsible for Business Discount Program (BDP) membership at 225% to the district average, BDP sales penetration was 35.2% compared to a company goal of 20% of sales.
- > Grew Average Order Volume over 10% for three consecutive years.
- ➤ Coordinated print projects through multiple 3rd party vendors.
- Supervised purchasing procedures of department and managed within company goals.
- > Established effective workflows to ensure customers projects were done right the first time and within customer time requirements.
- ➤ Copy center customer service satisfaction scores (CopySat) and customer quality satisfaction scores (QSAT) were consistently greater than company average by over 5%.
- Nominated 3 consecutive years by the District Manager for the Staples Team Care Award.

MARV

FEDEX KINKO'S, Mount Laurel, NJ, Philadelphia, PA

2000 to 2007

Center Manager

Headed the Grand Opening of a new Kinko's center in 2003. Areas of responsibility included recruitment, training and development of a new team along with developing the facility from an empty location to an operating center in ten days. Selected as trainer for integrating FedEx services into established Kinko's locations. Trained team members and management personnel for the entire Philadelphia market (32 stores) while managing own center.

- Established new client base in Center City Philadelphia that enabled the center to start turning a profit within 4 months, a full year ahead of company expectations.
- ➤ Initiated turnaround procedures in 3 underperforming centers and developed all 3 into successful profit generating centers.
- Assisted in performing district audits for HR compliance, financial and quality control.
- Nominated in 2003 by peer group and selected by the Kinko's Executive Committee as the Outstanding Kinko's Performer for The Northeast Region based on my "dedication to my work, my customers and my fellow team members".

RUBY'S DINER, Cherry Hill, NJ

1998 to 2000

General Manager

Responsible for operating a family themed restaurant. Recruited, trained and developed workers in all aspects of the food service industry including food preparation, sanitation, federal regulation compliance, safety and customer service. Managed supply costs including food and small ware purchases. Performed various financial activities such as cash handling, deposit preparation, payroll, forecasting and profit / loss preparation.

- ➤ Acquired restaurant which was losing \$200,000 a fiscal quarter. Within 4 months the restaurant was breaking even, increased sales at 95% to previous year and improved quality of operation to a level of being in the top 20% of company internal measures.
- ➤ Developed new systems for purchasing and production that decreased food cost by 8% and initiated labor standards and scheduling which lowered payroll costs by 8%.

BOSTON MARKET, Southern NJ

1994 to 1998

Multi Unit General Manager

Oversaw the day to day operations of up to three restaurants. Actively involved in the startup operations of restaurants in the Philadelphia market. Became regional training restaurant for managers in training.

- ➤ Developed for promotion 3 General Managers, 7 Assistant Managers and 7 Hourly Shift Supervisors in 18 months.
- ➤ Teamed with District Manager in analyzing operational issues in the district. Established and implemented procedures to alleviate those issues resulting in increased sales and profits.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts with High Honors, Business Management, GPA 3.67, Rutgers University Associate of Arts in Business Administration, GPA 3.36, Burlington County College, NJ